valuevillage.com 2019-04-08

# Privacy Policy | Value Village

Effective Date:   June 20, 2018

TVI, Inc. (“TVI”), doing business as Savers, Value Village, and Unique stores and VALUE VILLAGE STORES (“VALUE VILLAGE”), doing business as Value Village and Village des Valeurs (jointly “Savers”), are committed to protecting your privacy. To make your experience at our website more convenient and enable participation in programs like the Super Savers Club Card®, Super Savers Club™ and FUNDrive® programs, we gather information from you. As detailed below, we maintain the privacy of your information using secure technologies and adhere to policies that help prevent unauthorized use of your personal information.

By visiting our websites, including [www.savers.com](https://www.savers.com/) and [www.valuevillage.com](https://www.valuevillage.com/),  and any other online sites, social media or related online apps operated by Savers (the “Sites”), or by subscribing to any interactive features, email programs and newsletters, and other regular communications (“Programs”) or otherwise interacting with Savers you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Statement. 

**We reserve the right to modify or amend the terms of our Privacy Statement from time to time without notice. Your continued use of our Sites and Programs following the posting of changes to these terms will mean you accept those changes.   If we intend to apply the modifications or amendments to this Privacy Statement retroactively or to personal information already in our possession, we will provide you with notice of the modifications or amendments.**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement or don’t see your concerns addressed here, you should contact us by email at customercare@savers.com.

**What Information Do We Collect, and How Is It Used?**  
We collect certain information (a) when you voluntarily give us information; and (b) automatically when you visit our Sites or participate in our Programs.  As described below, we also may combine different sources of information, and may participate in interest-based advertising.

_Information You Give Us_  
We collect personal information, i.e. information that can individually identify you, such as first and last name, address, email address and telephone number (“Personal Information”), volunteered by our customers and visitors to our Sites, such as when you participate in a survey, newsletter, contest, sweepstakes, and/or website registrations. We also collect Personal Information you provide when you participate in Programs such as the Super Savers Club Card® and Super Savers Club™ customer loyalty programs or FUNDrive® fundraising program.  We also collect information you provide when you send us customer service or support requests or otherwise communicate with us through the Sites.

In those instances where we do collect Personal Information, you have a choice about what information to provide to us. Examples of when you voluntarily submit this kind of information include when you answer our surveys, fill out the registration form, enter a contest or send us feedback.

_Information Collected Automatically and Non-Personal Information_  
In addition to the Personal Information we collect directly from you, we may receive or collect some information when you visit the Sites or engage with other online content.  For example, we may receive the IP address of the computer or other device you use to access the Sites, which may tell us general geographic location.  We may also identify device information about your computer, browser or mobile device.  We also monitor and track usage of our Sites, viewing and traffic patterns, customer behavior and other similar information and in some cases we produce analytics and usage information based on such behavior.  We may also collect non-identifiable demographic data such as age, gender, or general geographic location. For more information on automatic collection of information from our Sites, see Use of Cookies, below.

_Combined Information_  
We use aggregate information collected automatically as well as Personal Information you provide to us for internal business and administrative purposes, including to improve our Sites and Programs, our operations and our customer service.  We may also use the information to better communicate with you and enhance our customer service and your shopping experience.

_Information Collected Through Social Media Sites_  
When you interact with any of our pages or accounts on a social media platform, such as Facebook, Twitter, Google+, Tumblr, LinkedIn, YouTube, or Pinterest, we may collect and use the Personal Information that you make available to us on that page or account including your account ID or “handle.” However, we will comply with the privacy policies of the corresponding social media platform and we will only collect and store such Personal Information that we are permitted to collect by these social media platforms. 

**How Do We Use Your Information?  **  
We use the information we collect from you to help us personalize and continually improve your experience with the Sites and Programs.  We may use your Personal Information and non-personal information in the following ways:

  * To communicate with you about promotions and other information we think will be of interest to you, at all times in accordance with applicable anti-spam laws
  * To communicate with you about your account or transactions with us (including service related announcements) and send you information about features and enhancements on our Sites and Programs
  * To communicate with you about changes to our policies
  * To manage your profile in Programs you participate in, such as the Super Savers Club Card® and Super Savers Club™ programs
  * To personalize content and experiences on our Sites and in our Programs, including providing you reports, recommendations and feedback based on your preferences
  * To disclose anonymized Personal Information used to compile statistics and analytics and other details regarding the use of our Sites and/or Programs.
  * To optimize or improve our products, services and operations
  * To automatically update the Sites on your device
  * To detect, investigate, and prevent activities that may violate our policies or be illegal
  * To perform statistical, demographic, and marketing analyses of users of the Sites and Programs

_Online Advertising_    
We may use cookies and similar tools in combination with other information you provide to us to participate in interest-based or targeted advertising.  This means that you may see ads on the Sites or other parties' websites based on the way you browse our Sites and other parties’ websites.  For more information on your choices regarding our collection of information and advertising, see Use of Cookies.

_Email Services_  
When you sign up for one of our Programs and consent to receive email messages, you consent to receive such messages at the email address you provide to us.  See below for information on how to unsubscribe from email messages.  Please note that some Programs require that you consent to receive email notifications regarding the Program terms.

_Text Messaging Services_  
When you sign up for one of our Programs and consent to receive text messages, you consent to receive such messages on your mobile phone or other mobile device about our products, services, and/or Programs which may be sent by automated means. Text messages will only be sent to the mobile phone number used to opt into the applicable Program. In some instances, you may have the opportunity to reply to a message, which may result in additional response messages. Your consent to enrollment in a Program that includes text messages is not a condition of purchase. Message and data rates may apply. This means that your carrier may charge you for each message we send to you or that you send to us. It is your responsibility to know whether your carrier will charge you a per-message fee. We do not charge a fee for our text message programs and assume no responsibility for charges by your carrier you may incur when you sign up to receive text messages from us. You may opt out of a text message program at any time by following the instructions linked in the text message. You will receive a final confirmation message that will confirm that you will no longer receive text messages from the applicable text message program unless you opt back into such program.

**Protecting Your Privacy; Sharing with Third Parties**  
As part of our commitment to ensuring the privacy of our customers, except as disclosed in this Privacy Statement, we do not sell or exchange Personal Information about our customers with third parties, unless they are subsidiaries, affiliates, or trusted business partners. Although, as disclosed below, we may provide your information to our business partners and third-party agents, in no event will we sell or rent your Personal Information as part of a customer list or similar transaction, except as detailed in this Privacy Statement or as authorized by law.

_Business Partners_  
We may share your Personal Information with our business partners and co-marketer third parties from time to time, in compliance with applicable anti-spam laws.  You may withdraw your consent to such sharing of your Personal Information with business partners at any time by following the opt-out process described below.

_Third-Party Agents_  
We have third party agents, subsidiaries, affiliates and partners that perform functions on our behalf, such as hosting, billing, push notifications, storage, bandwidth, content management tools, analytics, customer service, fraud protection, etc.  These entities have access to the Personal Information needed to perform their functions and are contractually obligated to maintain the confidentiality and security of that Personal Information.  They are restricted from using, selling, or distributing your Personal Information in any way other than to provide the requested services to the Sites.

_Legal Compliance_  
We may also use or disclose Personal Information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to (a) conform to applicable law or comply with legal process served on us or the Sites; (b) protect and defend our rights or property, the Sites or Programs or our users, and (c) act under emergency circumstances to protect the personal safety of us, our affiliates, agents, or the users of the Sites or Programs or the public.  This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection.

_Use of Non-Personal Information_  
We may disclose or share non-personal information (or other information, other than Personal Information) in any other manner that we deem appropriate or necessary. Among other things, we may disclose non-personal information to third parties to help us determine how people use parts of the Sites and Programs and who our users are so we can improve our Sites and Programs.  We may also disclose non-personal information to our business partners and other third parties about how our users collectively use the Sites.

**What Steps Are Taken to Keep Personal Information Secure?**  
We are concerned about ensuring the security of your Personal Information.  We use industry standard security techniques to help protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information we collect.  Our security procedures mean that we may occasionally request proof of identity before we disclose your Personal Information to you.  Please understand, however, that while we try our best to safeguard your Personal Information once we receive it, no transmission of data over the Internet or any other public network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. 

_Children’s Privacy_  
Our Sites are general audience sites that are not directed at children under the age of 13. Savers does not knowingly ask for or collect Personal Information from children under 13 or from children between the age of 13 and 16 without verifiable parental consent.  If Savers learns that a child under the age of 16 has submitted Personal Information to us without parental consent, we will take all reasonable measures to delete such information and/or not use such information for any purpose.  If you become aware of any Personal Information we have collected from a child under 16, please contact us at customercare@savers.com.

**How Can We Transfer Your Personal Information?**  
Your information collected through the Sites and Programs may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which Savers, its Affiliates or service providers maintain facilities.  Savers, its Affiliates, or service providers may transfer information that we collect about you, including Personal Information across borders and from your country or jurisdiction to other countries or jurisdictions around the world.  Please note that we may transfer information, including Personal Information, to a country and jurisdiction that does not have the same data protection laws as your jurisdiction and that such Personal Information may therefore be available to government authorities under lawful orders and laws applicable there.  Wherever your Personal Information is transferred, stored, or processed by Savers _,_ Savers will take reasonable steps to safeguard the privacy of your Personal Information _.   _By registering for and using the Sites you consent to the transfer of information to the U.S. or to any other country in which Savers, its Affiliates or service providers maintain facilities and the use and disclosure of information about you as described in this Privacy Statement. 

**How Long Do We Keep Your Information?**  
Following termination or deactivation of your account, Savers, its Affiliates, or its service providers may retain Personal Information (including your profile information) for a commercially reasonable time for backup, archival, and/or audit purposes, at all times in accordance with applicable laws.  If you have any questions about termination or deactivation of your account, please contact us directly at customercare@savers.com.

**Opt-Out Provisions**  
 _Choosing to Provide Personal Information_  
Visitors to our Sites and participants in our Programs can choose not to provide the Personal Information needed to register for the services and communications offered by Savers; however, they may not be able to use the services and communications without providing some types of Personal Information.

_Email Communications_  
If you would like to opt out of receiving email communications from us, you may do so at any time by clicking the unsubscribe button or following other unsubscribe instructions found in the email message.  Please note that this may affect your ability to access certain products and services, and we may continue to send non-promotional communications such as staffing confirmations, program information, surveys, and other information about the Sites and/or Programs. In some jurisdictions, we may provide the tool to allow you to refer others using our email functionality, in compliance with applicable anti-spam laws. If you refer others to us using our email functionality, please note that they may choose not to receive any promotional emails from us in the future by following the opt-out instructions in the email invitation.

You may choose not to share your precise geo-location information with us by adjusting your device's location services settings or the settings on our mobile applications.

_Use of Cookies_  
Cookies are pieces of information that are stored on your computer and are used for record keeping purposes. We use cookies or similar technologies to make visiting and using our Sites easier. Cookies can help us see which parts of our Sites are the most or least popular and provide us direction to improve our customer's online experience. We may also use them to help us provide you with a customized experience and interest-based or targeted ads and promotions, as described above.  You may stop or limit our ability to collect information from you when you visit our Sites by disabling “cookies” or using other privacy features that may be available on your website browser. If you delete your cookies or if you set your web browser to decline cookies, some features of the Sites may not work or may not work as designed.  We may also partner with third party advertising companies to better provide advertisements about our goods and services that may be of interest to you.  These third party advertisers may use cookies alone or in conjunction with web beacons or other tracking technologies to collect information about you when you use the Sites.  They may collect information about your online activities over time and across different websites and other online services.  They may use this information to provide you with interest-based advertising or other targeted content.  We do not provide these online advertising partners access to your name, address, email address, telephone number or other Personal Information.  They may, however, use persistent identifiers to anonymously track your Internet usage across other websites in their networks beyond these Sites.  While we restrict their further use of such information, such third parties may, with sufficient data from other sources, be able to personally identify you, unknown to us.

_Do Not Track_  
Your browser or device may include “Do Not Track” functionality. Because a “Do Not Track” compliance protocol has not yet been finalized, Savers’ information collection and disclosure practices, and the choices that we provide to customers, will continue to operate as described in this Privacy Policy, whether or not a Do Not Track signal is received.

_Links to Other Sites_  
The Sites may provide links to websites operated by third parties. While we choose our links carefully, we cannot take any responsibility for the content of linked websites, or for the privacy policies of websites we link to. Since we do not control these websites, we encourage you to review the privacy policies posted on these third party websites prior to any use.

**What About Contests, Sweepstakes or Games?**  
When we run a contest or sweepstakes or game relating to our Sites or Programs, it will be accompanied by a set of rules. The rules for each contest, sweepstakes or game will specify how the information gathered from you for entry will be used and disclosed if it is different than as described in this Privacy Statement.  In conjunction with your entry in such contest or sweepstakes, Personal Information will be collected only if you voluntarily submit it; though participation in the contest or sweepstakes may require that you provide some Personal Information.

_Assignment and Business Transaction_  
We may change our ownership or corporate organization while providing the Sites and Programs.  We may also sell certain assets associated with the Sites and Programs.  As a result, please be aware that in such event we may transfer some or all of your information to a company acquiring all or part of our assets or to another company with which we have merged.  Under such circumstances we would, to the extent possible, require the acquiring party to follow the practices described in this Privacy Statement, as it may be amended from time to time and we will comply with privacy laws applicable in your jurisdiction which may require us to provide you with notifications.  Nevertheless, in the event the transaction is completed, your Personal Information will remain protected by privacy laws applicable in your jurisdiction, although we cannot promise that an acquiring company or the merged company will have the same privacy practices or treat your information the same as described in this Privacy Statement.

**For more information**  
If you have any further questions regarding our privacy practices or you wish to access and/or update your Personal Information, please email us at customercare@savers.com or contact us at

Savers/Value Village  
Headquarters Address  
11400 S.E. 6th Street, Suite 220  
Bellevue, WA 98004  
Telephone: (425) 462-1515  
Fax: (425) 451-2250

**_Your California Privacy Rights_**  
California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits customers of Savers who are California residents to request certain information regarding its disclosure of their Personal Information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an email to customercare@savers.com.
